Guide to the Center for International Studies records, 1960-1983.
Center for International Studies records
- Series XI. Wider Cornell University Committees and Affairs
  - Campus Unrest, 1969
    - Minutes of the Special Meeting of the Faculty, April 16-28, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Minutes of the Special Meeting of the Faculty, May 2, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - "Cornell University Regulations for the Maintenance of Public Order", July 15, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - "Inside Report" on Anti-Semitism and Racism at Cornell, Including Reactions, July 21-24, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Excerpts from a Transcript of a Speech Made by Tom Jones at Willard Straight Hall (on race issues) on June 29, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - "Report of the Ad Hoc Judiciary Committee", August 28, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - "Procedures to be followed in the event of classroom disruption", September 5, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Course Descriptions
    - "Current Issues in Science, Technology, and Public Policy", Spring 1969 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Descriptions of Government Courses, Fall 1974 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Assorted Course Descriptions, Spring 1971 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Papers on International Studies Courses and Curricula, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Course Descriptions, Has details for CIS211: Peasants, Power, and Productivity, as well as CIS212: Ethnicity, Race, and Communalism (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Papers and Correspondence Concerning CIS Courses (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Budget Strife
    - "Recommendations Task Force Number 13-Publications", April 30, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - "Task Force #8: Centers and Interdisciplinary Programs, Final Report", May 16, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - "Task Force #8: Centers and Interdisciplinary Programs, Final Report", May 16, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Pearson Memorandum of June 11 on Restricted Funds, July 3, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Bill Whyte's Response to Task Force Proposals, September 1975 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Further Papers on Task Force 8, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Selections from McNeil Report, Task Force 8 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - CIS University Funds Budget, 1975-1976 Fiscal Year, 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Responses to Task Force 8 Report, April-August 1976 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Board of Trustees
    - Extract from Minutes of Board of Trustees, January 18-19, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "The Report of the Trustee Ad Hoc Committee on Capital Financing," Cornell University, January 1975 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Papers on the Board of Trustees and Cornell University By-Laws, March-April 1975 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Assorted Comments Concerning the Board of Trustees, June 16, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - "By-Laws of Cornell University, As Amended to October 13, 1972" (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Papers Related to Cornell University Senate, July 1972-May 1974 (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - By-Laws of Cornell University, As Amended Through June 2, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - By-Laws of Cornell University as Amended Through June 1, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - International Studies
    - Papers on the Office of International Studies, 1963-1973 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - International Studies Major, 1968-1978 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - International Studies Major: Course Listing, 1971-1972 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - I.S.A. Membership Drive, 1971-1977 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - International Studies Major, 1971-1972 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Cornell University Council Correspondence and Papers, 1967-1975 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Cornell University Council Membership, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Bylaws of Cornell University as Amended Through January 19, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Cornell Newsletter and Related Papers, May 28, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - University Committees: Presidential Commission on Student Participation in Decision-Making (Morison Commission), August 29, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - PE and PP Seminars, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - PPLMS Staff Visitors (Box 2, Folder 120)
  - PPLMS Staff/Faculty Director (Box 2, Folder 121)
  - Program for the Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences Conference, December 8, 1976 (Box 6)
  - Structural Change Committee Papers, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Structural Change Committee, September 1969-December 1969 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - PPLMS: Towards a Fully Self-Managed Industrial Sector in the United States (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - A Contract College of the State University at Cornell University, Ithaca, New York: International Home Economics Project, 1965-1975, April 1966 (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - Future Plans for College of Architecture, February 3, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Report to the Governing Board, Center for Housing and Environmental Studies for the Division of Urban Studies, by Barclay Jones for the period September 28, 1966-November 17, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - The New York State College of Agriculture and the Next Quarter Century, Late 1960s (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - N.Y.S. School of ILR (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - Correspondence About Scientific/Technological CIS Programs, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - N.Y.S. School of ILR, March 30, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - "Draft Proposal to Organize a Planning Team for ECAFE's Diagnosed Regional Center for Technology Group", April 18, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Booklets on "Cornell in the Seventies", 1973 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Provost Office-Related Papers, September 1974 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - "Report of the Director of the Priorities Study to President Dale R. Corson", June 27, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Awards Made for Study During 1965-1966 Academic Year, 1965-1966 (Box 10, Folder 101)
  - Assorted Papers on Financial Support for Language Studies, 1965-1970, 1965-1970 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Architecture: Regional Planning, 1960s (Box 15, Folder 56)
  - Courses up to 1969-1970 Academic Year (CIS Courses) (Box 15, Folder 57)
  - ISRP: Proposal to HEW, October 1972 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - International Studies and Regional Planning, 1972-1976 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Reports-Int'l Stds. in Regional Planning (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Annual Reports of the Director of University Libraries, 1967-1975 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Payroll Papers, 1970s (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Intl. Student Office, 1972-1973 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Intl. Student Office, 1973-1974 (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Intl. Student Office, 1974-1976 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Institute of International Education, 1974-1976 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Support to International Programs, 1971-1972 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - University Policy on Surveys, April 17, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Crisis - "Library", 1972-1973 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Papers on University Lecturers, 1971-1976 (Box 18, Folder 66)
  - Tuition Assistance Program, 1972-1976 (Box 18, Folder 67)
  - Papers About Throwing Events at the Statler, 1973-1976 (Box 18, Folder 71)
  - Instructions for Issuing Form DSP-66 Certificate of Eligibility for Exchange Visitor Status, June 14, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 72)
  - "Report of the Senate Summer Study Group", August 27, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 74)
  - Bylaws of Cornell University, As Amended Through May 29, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 75)
  - American Universities Field Staff, 1970s (Box 18, Folder 76)
  - Discussion of Scholarship Between William F. Whytes and Lee W. Huff, October 1, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 85)
  - Correspondence Between Cornell and the American Institute of Indian Studies, 1967-1972 (Box 18, Folder 86)
  - Correspondence Concerning Project to Honor Arthur H. Dean, April-July 1973 (Box 18, Folder 87)
  - Correspondence About the Mailing Services of SEAP Publications Office, February-July 1975 (Box 18, Folder 88)
  - Assorted Correspondence Concerning Cornell Affairs (Box 18, Folder 89)
  - "Policy Governing Research and Teaching with Human Beings as Subjects", June 30, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 90)
  - Faculty Protest Against Cornell Policy, Spring 1969 (Box 18, Folder 91)
  - Correspondence and Papers About Public Policy, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 92)
  - Cornell Gift Policy, August 20, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 93)
  - International Student Office, 1968-1977 (Box 17, Folder 24)
- Series XII. Publications
  - "Models for Building and Changing Organizations", 1967 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - "The Role of the US Professor in Developing Countries", February 1969 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Reprint of "The American Economic Review", December 1969 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Chinoperl News No. 2, December 1970 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Unitar News, Volume 6., 1974 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Brochure on the International Association for the Exchange of Students for Technical Experience (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - The Dissolution of HAP, Cornell's Human Affairs Program, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Series XIII. Assorted Documents
  - Documents Concerning CIS' Place in the Social Sciences Building, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - CIS Research and Research Policy Documents, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Mid-Penninsula Observer, Article on Stanford Research Institute in Thailand, Possibly 1967 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Foreign Assistance Act (Title IX) Documents, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Board on Science and Technology for International Development, June 1969 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - The Cornell Program on Science, Technology, and Society, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Description of the Office of Science and Technology (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Previous Years' Seminars (prior to 1971-1972) (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Seminars (prior to 1972-1973) (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - In Memoriam: Leonard Reissman (1921-1975) (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - English-Indo Dictionary General (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - General (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - International Agricultural Development Committee Papers, 1965-1969 (Box 2, Folder 122)
  - Research and Training Opportunities Abroad and Foreign Curriculum Consultants in the US", 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 123)
  - DML-Staff, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - DML-Ford Foundation, 1965-1973 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - DML-Financial Data, 1968-1972 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - DML-Organization (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Federal Agencies-General, 1964-1973 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Peace Corps RPCV's (Returned Peace Corps Volunteers), 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Peace Corps Liaison, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Parking Correspondence, 1967-1972 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Parking Regulations, 1967-1973 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Luce Foundation, 1967-1973 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - External Fund Sources, General, 1967-1973 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Hazen Foundation, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Peace Corps Training, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Kettering Foundation, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Alumni Group, 1970-1976 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Smithsonian Institution, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - O.E. "Redirections" (NDEA 72), 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Program on Participation and Labor-Managed Systems, 1971-1976 (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Workshop on Modernizing Agriculture, 1971-1977 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - National Endowment for Humanities, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Assorted Cornell-Related Papers (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - IISS 14th Annual Conference, September 14-17, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Assorted Documents, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - "Frost Lines," Agency for International Development, Washington, D.C., March 25, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "The Data Problem in International Communication," Mass Media Project, Royal Collection (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - The Washington Office: A Service of International Advisory Services, INC. (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - United Nations, April 1973-May 1973 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - O.E. "redirections", 1973 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Report of the Informal Committee on a Program for Federal Action, October 17, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Special Projects: General (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - "Agreement Between the Government of the United States of America and Cornell University", June 25, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 77)
  - "Higher Education Programs in Foreign Language and Area Studies, 1970-1971 (Box 10, Folder 81)
  - Papers from the World Studies Data Bank, Early 1970s (Box 10, Folder 96)
  - Brochures and Papers for the Institute for World Order, Summer 1976 (Box 10, Folder 97)
  - Institute for International Order Brochure (Box 10, Folder 99)
  - Czech. Refuggee Material, April 1967-October 1968 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - "Objectives and Policies for the Master's Program,"Graduate School of Business and Public Administration-Cornell University, May 25, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Ad Hoc Committee, Golay Report, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Assorted Papers Concerning Advertizing and Alumni, April-November 1976 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - United States Government: "Studies in Facilitating Learning, Communication Technology (Policy and Training)", 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Cornell Committee on Exchange (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Student Recruitment Printed Materials (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Comparative Economic Development Papers, 1966-1973 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Comparative Economic Development Grants/Awards, 1967-1970 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Comparative Economic Development Program, 1968-1699 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Assorted Comparative Economics Papers (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Conference on Problems of Nuclear Proliferation, March 18-21, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 45)
  - Conference on 'The Sources of Discontent and Institutional Innovation in Advanced Industrial Societies,', March 21-23, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 46)
  - Conference Group on Italian Politics, May 1974 (Box 16, Folder 47)
  - Conference Group on French Politics and Society, Summer 1974 (Box 16, Folder 48)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 49)
  - City University of New York, European Community Studies, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 50)
  - Annual Report: Vice President for Research and Advanced Studies, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 61)
  - Report of the Ad Hoc Committee on the Project of a World University and a Proposal for Further Study of the Subject, Winter 1969 (Box 18, Folder 62)
  - Non Students Inquiries, 1970-1971 (Box 18, Folder 64)
  - Discussion of University Taxes, 1971-1975 (Box 18, Folder 65)
  - Budget Ledger, Travel by Person, 1980 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Budget Ledger, Travel by Project, 1978-1979 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Budget Ledger, Travel by Project, 1980-1981 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Budget Ledger, Rural Debelopment Participation Project Salaries, 1978-1981 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Budget Ledger, Rural Debelopment Participation Project Salaries by Project, 1978-1981 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - 1980 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Appendix III
    - Program of Research and Training on Center-Periphery Tensions in Western Europe: Second Annual Report to the Ford Foundation, January-December 1975 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Renewal and Application Comparative Policy Program (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Peace Studies Program, Third Annual Report, July 1974-December 1975 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - "Science Policy Development in France and Germany and its Relevance to US Science Policy" (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Charter for an Energy Policy Studies Unit (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - The Society for the Humanities (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Peace Studies Program Third Annual Report, July 1974-December 1975 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - NSF Grant for "Research on Science Policy: An Interrelated Group of Studies" (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Charter for an Energy Policy Studies Unit (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Conference on Ethnic Pluralism and Conflict in Contemporary Western Europe and Canada (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Series XIV. Correspondence
  - Correspondence for CIS Library Support, August 1968-September 1968 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Correspondence Concerning Science and Technology, 1969-1978 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Assorted CIS Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Assorted Correspondence, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Assorted Correspondence, 1971-1976 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Correspondence About Reprinting Arthur Lall's Negotiating Disarmament, March 1976 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Correspondence and Abstracts for "An Empirical and Theoretical Investigation of the Participatory Economy", 1970-1975 (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - World Data Bank, December 1972 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Ford Foundation Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Ford Foundation Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Assorted Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Assorted Papers, Mainly Correspondence, 1971-1974 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Positions Occupied by Returned MIT Fellows (as of September 15, 1965), September 15, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 70)
  - "A Manual of Procedures for Participating Institutions," from US Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 74)
  - Douglas Ashford Correspondence, 1962-1969 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Steven Muller Correspondence Concerning International Affairs, April 1967-April 1969 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Assorted CIS Correspondence from Joan Irving, June-November 1982 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence from Milton J. Esman, June-December 1982; Also includes several references and letters of recommendation. (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Assorted Papers Related to Professor Jaroslav Vanek, 1968-1972 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Assorted Visitor Correspondence, 1968-1972 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence: November 1967 to March 1968 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence: April 1968 to June 1968 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence: July 1968 to September 1968 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence: October 1968 to November 1968 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence: December 1968 to January 15, 1969 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence: January 16, 1969 to February 20, 1969 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence: February 19, 1969 to March 27, 1969 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence: March 28, 1969 to June 30, 1969 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence: July 1, 1969 to October 31, 1969 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence: November 1, 1969 to January 30, 1970 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence: February 1970 to April 1970 (Box 20)
  - CIS Correspondence: May 1, 1970 to July 23, 1970 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence: July 24, 1970 to October 31, 1970 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence: November 2, 1970 to December 31, 1970 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence: January 4, 1971 to April 9, 1971 (Box 20)
  - Chronological Files: April 12, 1971 to May 31, 1971 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence: June 1, 1971 to September 1, 1971 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence: September 3, 1971 to December 30, 1971 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence: December 23, 1971 to April 28, 1972 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence: May 1, 1972 to July 31, 1872 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence: August 1 to September 30, 1972 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence:October 1, 1972 to November 30, 1972 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence: December 1972 to January 1973 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence: February 1, 1973 to March 30, 1973 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence: April 1, 1973 to May 31, 1973 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence: May 1973 to July 27, 1973 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence: July 27, 1973 to September 25, 1973 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence: September 5, 1973 to October 30, 1973 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence: October 31, 1973 to December 28, 1973 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence: January 1, 1974 to March 31, 1974 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence: April 1, 1974 to June 28, 1974 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence: July 1, 1974 to September 30, 1974 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence: October 1, 1974 to November 27, 1974 (Box 23)
  - Correspondence: November 1, 1974 to January 30, 1975 (Box 23)
  - Correspondence: February 1, 1975 to March 31, 1975 (Box 23)
  - Correspondence: April 1, 1975 to May 31, 1975 (Box 23)
  - Correspondence: June 2, 1975 to August 29, 1975 (Box 23)
  - Correspondence: September 1, 1975 to November 28, 1975 (Box 23)
  - Correspondence: December 1, 1975 to February 29, 1976 (Box 24)
  - Correspondence: March 1, 1976 to May 31, 1976 (Box 24)
  - Correspondence: June 1, 1976 to September 30, 1976 (Box 24)
  - Correspondence: October 1, 1976 to November 22, 1976 (Box 24)
  - Correspondence: November 23, 1976 to January 24, 1977 (Box 24)
  - Correspondence: January 25, 1977 to March 24, 1977 (Box 24)
  - Correspondence: March 25, 1977 to May 12, 1977 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: May 13, 1977 to June 30, 1977 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: June 23, 1977 to September 9, 1977 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: September 9, 1977 to October 25, 1977 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: October 25, 1977 to December 5, 1977 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence: December 7, 1977 to January 23, 1978 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence and Chrono.: January 23, 1978 to February 22, 1978 (Box 26)
  - Correspondence and Chrono.: February 17, 1978 to March 31, 1978 (Box 26)
  - Correspondence and Chrono.: March 17, 1978 to May 10, 1978 (Box 26)
  - Correspondence and Chrono.: May 8, 1978 to June 30, 1978 (Box 26)
  - Correspondence and Chrono.: July 1978 to September 1978 (Box 26)
  - Correspondence and Chrono.: September 1978 to October 1978 (Box 26)
  - Correspondence and Chrono.: November 1978 to January 1979 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence and Chrono.: November 1978 to January 1979 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence and Chrono.: January 10, 1979 to March 7, 1979 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence and Chrono.: January 22, 1979 to March 12, 1979 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence and Chrono.: March 5, 1979 to April 27, 1979 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence and Chrono.: March 12, 1979 to June 21, 1979 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence and Chrono.: June 14, 1979 to September 18, 1979 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence and Chrono.: September 10, 1979 to October 31, 1979 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence and Chrono.: November 6, 1979 to January 4, 1980 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence and Chrono.: January 4, 1980 to March 5, 1980 (Box 28)
  - Correspondence and Chrono.: March 3, 1980 to May 9, 1980 (Box 28)
  - Correspondence and Chrono.: May 13, 1980 to July 31, 1980 (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence and reports, 1980 (Box 28, Folder 1)
- Series XV. Research, Articles, and Presentations
  - Articles Concerning Race Relations
    - "African Traditional Thought and Western Science," by Robin Horton, from "Africa", 1967 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - "Guidelines for a Study of the Effectiveness of Policies and Measures Against Racial Discrimination", February 1968 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - "Color in World Affairs," by Harold R. Issacs, in "Foreign Affairs", January 1969 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - "The Challenges of Race - From Entrenched White Power to Rising Black Power," by Locksley Edmondson, from "International Journal", Autumn 1969 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - "Multiracial Politics in the New States: Toward a Theory of Conflict," by Donald L. Horowitz, September 1969 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - "Ethnology and the Peace of South Asia," by Walker Connor, from "World Politics: A Quarterly Journal of International Relations", October 1969 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - "Academic Ignorance and Black Intelligence," by William Labov, from the "Atlantic Monthly", June 1972 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - "The Development of Underdevelopment," by Andre Gunder Frank, from "Imperialism and Underdevelopment" (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Preface of "Pedagogy of the Oppressed," by Paulo Freire (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Chapter 1 of "Pedagogy of the Oppressed" (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - "The Pitfalls of National Consciousness-Africa," by Franz Fanon, from "Wretched of the Earth" (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Summaries of Racial Situation in Various Countries (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Articles Concerning India
    - Indian Economic Association: 53rd Annual Conference, "From Stagnation to Growth: Relative Roles of Technology, Economic Policy and Agrarian Institutions", December 1970 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - "An Approach to the Sacred Cow of India," by Alan Hesten1, April 1971 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - "Delivery of Canal Water in North India and West Pakistan," by W. Eric Gustafson and Richard B. Reidinger, December 1971 (Box 9, Folder 31)